https://wizouk.org/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
WIZOuk is committed to protecting your privacy and the security of the personal information we receive about you when you interact with us by phone, mail, in person or online.
Being transparent about the way in which we collect and use your personal data is important to us and the purpose of this policy is to give you a clear explanation about how WIZOuk processes such data, our obligations to you and your rights. If you want to discuss any matter relating to how your data is used, please contact the Data Protection Officer on 020 7319 9169, email DPO@wizouk.org or write to WIZOuk, Charles House, 108-110 Finchley Road, London NW3 5JJ.
References to the processing of information includes the collection, use, storage and protection of data. WIZOuk is the ‘data controller’ for the purposes of this policy, and the policy extends to its staff, trustees, volunteers and anyone else processing data on our behalf from time to time. Any personal data collected by WIZOuk will only be processed in accordance with this privacy policy.
Developing a better understanding of our supporters through their personal data allows us to fundraise more efficiently, which ultimately helps us to change lives and build futures. We have made improvements to this policy so that transparency is at the core of what we do.
We ensure that we use your information in accordance with all applicable data protection laws and regulations concerning the protection of personal information. Our privacy policy explains the following:
What information WIZOuk may process about you
The legal basis for processing such information
How we will use that information and for how long we will keep it
Whether we disclose your details to anyone else
Your choices regarding the information you provide to us
How we use cookies to provide services to you or to improve your use of our website
This privacy policy also applies to the WIZOUK.org website and explains what happens to your personal information when you use the website or interact with us through it.
Who we are
WIZO is the largest social welfare organisation in Israel helping vulnerable and disadvantaged Israeli citizens regardless of age, race or religion. Our registered charity number is 1125012 in England and Wales. We are also registered as a company limited by guarantee in England under registration number 6634748.
How we collect information about you
We collect information in the following ways:
Information you give us. For example, when you engage with our social media, make a donation to us, become a member, register for an event or otherwise provide us with or update your personal information. When you register, we will ask for personal information, like your name, email and/or postal address and telephone number, payment information and whether you are a tax payer so that we can claim Gift Aid.
Information we get from your use of our website and services. We collect information about the services you use when you visit our website.
Information from third parties. We may also receive information about you from third parties. This can include information such as your name, postal address, email address, phone number, your geographic location (for mobile devices), credit/debit card details.  We, like all companies, are able to confirm what browser you are using, IP address and computer operating systems that are being used and this information may be used to improve the services we offer.
Photographic and video images. Such images may be recorded at our events for the purposes of marketing and promoting WIZOuk, including on social media. As with all other uses of personal data, may you ask us not to take, retain or use any such images of you. No such images will knowingly be processed when they relate to children under the age of 16 without the permission of a person legally responsible for that child.
CCTV. We operate CCTV in our office premises for the purpose of security which is registered with the Office of the Information Commissioner for that purpose. Images will not be retained for longer than is necessary for these purposes except in the case of the investigation of security, criminal or staff conduct issues. Images will only be shared with the relevant law enforcement agencies and/or the Community Security Trust pursuant to the investigation or prosecution of a suspected or actual criminal offence.
Wherever possible we collect aggregated or anonymous information which does not identify individual visitors to our websites. See below, under marketing materials, to understand our purposes for processing your personal information.
Data Protection law recognises that certain categories of personal information are more sensitive. This is known as sensitive personal data and covers health information, race, religious beliefs and political opinions. We do not routinely collect ‘sensitive personal data’ about our supporters but will tell you if we need to for any reason.
Our legal basis for processing your information
Organisations are permitted to process data if they have a legal basis for doing so. WIZOuk processes data on the basis that:
Express and informed consent has been given by the person whose data is being processed; and/or
WIZOuk has a legitimate interest in processing the data; and/or
It is necessary in relation to a contract or agreement which the person has entered into or because the person has asked for something to be done so they can enter into a contract or agreement; and/or
WIZOuk has a legal obligation to process data.
Where WIZOuk is relying solely on consent as the basis for processing data, we are required to obtain your explicit consent and you can modify or withdraw this consent at any time by notifying us in writing, although this may affect the extent to which we are able to provide services to or interact with you in future.
How we use information about you
We use your data to:
Provide you with the services, products or information you have asked for (for example, when you purchase an item from our online shop).
Administer your donation or support your fundraising activities, including processing Gift Aid.
Keep a record of and administer your relationship with us as a supporter, volunteer, member or member of staff.
Provide you with information about our work, fundraising campaigns or our activities that you have agreed to receive or that we think you may be interested in.
Manage your marketing preferences.
Understand how we can improve our services, products or information.
Comply with financial regulations and the law.
Your rights concerning your personal information
You have a right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. You also have the right to ask us not to process your information for marketing purposes or at all.
You can edit your WIZOuk account information, including your address and contact details at any time.
If you would like to change your communication preferences, update the details we hold about you or request details of the personal information we hold about you, please contact the Data Protection Officer on 020 7319 9169, email DPO@wizouk.org or write to WIZO UK, Charles House, 108-110 Finchley Road, London NW3 5JJ. We reserve the right to verify your identity before disclosing any personal information to you.
Direct Marketing
We want to ensure that you receive the level of information about WIZOuk that is right for you and you can change your preferences or decide that you do not want to hear from us at any time.
Email/text marketing:
Email and text marketing can be the most efficient and cost-effective means of telling you about our vital work, and about campaigns and promotions we think may be of interest to you. In order to be able to contact you in this way, we need your explicit consent, which we will ask for when you subscribe to WIZO UK for this service.
Post/telephone marketing:
If you have provided us with your postal address or telephone number we may send you direct mail or telephone you about our work unless you have told us that you would prefer not to receive such information.
It is always your choice as to how and whether you want to receive information about our work, campaigns, how we raise funds and the ways you can get involved. To update your preferences you can, where applicable
Click the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the end of our marketing emails.
Use any form that we have sent you, or any webpage where we collect information from you, or contact us directly using the details given above.
We will not use your personal information for marketing purposes if you have indicated that you do not wish to be contacted by us for such purposes. However, we will retain your details on a suppression list to help ensure that we do not continue to contact you.
Building profiles and targeting communications
It is important to us that your engagement with WIZOuk is a positive one. We therefore target our fundraising to ensure that we are contacting you with the most appropriate communications, which are relevant and timely and will ultimately provide an improved experience for you. In doing so, we may use profiling techniques or use third party screening and insight companies to allow us to focus our resources effectively, which donors consistently tell us is a key priority for them.
When building a profile, we may analyse geographic, demographic and other information relating to you in order to better understand your interests and preferences so that we can contact you with the most relevant communications. In doing this, we may use additional publicly available information, for example, listed directorships or typical earnings in a given area. We may use information filed at the Charity Commission, Companies House, Trustfunding.org, LinkedIn and The Sunday Times Rich List, or ask third parties to undertake these activities on our behalf.
We do this because it allows us to understand the background of the people who support us and helps us to make appropriate requests to supporters (individuals, charitable trusts/foundations and companies) who may be able and willing to give more than they already do and/or leave us a gift in their will. Importantly, it enables us to raise more funds, sooner, and more cost-effectively, than we otherwise would.
You can opt out of your data being used for profiling and screening techniques by contacting us using the details given above.
Who we share your information with
WIZOuk may disclose your personal information in the following circumstances:
To other WIZO entities, such as World WIZO in Israel, who may then update you with information about WIZO activities that they think may be of interest to you.
If we share your data with colleagues or trusted partners outside of the European Union, such as in Israel, we will only do so if we are confident that they adhere to the same high standards and legal obligations that we do when processing data and protecting its privacy and security.
To third parties who provide products or services either to us or that you have requested. This would include our trusted partners that work with us in connection with our charitable purposes, and other entities that provide WIZOuk information and marketing (subject to your communication preferences and our internal policies and procedures). We require these third parties to comply strictly with our instructions and data protection laws and we will make sure that appropriate controls are in place. We enter into contracts with all of our data processors and regularly monitor their activities to ensure they are complying with WIZOuk policies and procedures.
Where it is necessary or we are under a duty to disclose your personal information in order to comply with any legal requirement or obligation (for example to HMRC or other government bodies and law enforcement agencies), or in order to enforce or apply our rights (including in relation to our website or other applicable terms and conditions) or to protect WIZOuk, for example in cases of suspected fraud or defamation.
It is not the policy of WIZOuk to share, sell or swap your details with any third parties for the purposes of their own marketing or the monetizing of your data.
Website users
WIZOuk’s website uses cookies to help it work well and to track information about how people are using them. More information on cookies can be found further down the page under ‘Cookies’.
In addition, if you register for an event on our website then the following will also apply:
WIZOuk’s website collects personal information when you register with us.
We will collect information such as your name, email address and post code.
When we collect your personal information, we use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorised access. However, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. As a result, while we try to protect your personal information, WIZOuk cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk.
Cookies:
Cookies are small text files that are automatically placed onto your device by some websites that you visit. They are widely used to improve the performance of a website, for saving different options and to provide website owners with information on how the site is being used.
We use cookies to enhance the experience of our website, to increase the performance, to identify how the website is being used and where we can make improvements. Some of our cookies are vital for the website to operate effectively and others are optional but may decrease the usability or performance of the website. You may prefer to disable cookies on the website. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser.
Tracking:
We use multiple first and third-party technologies such as pixel tags and web beacons to track and improve the user experience on our sites, quality of service and to monitor the effectiveness of campaigns and digital marketing activity.
We may use them to see what website content is popular and how people are using the site as they allow us to track users’ movements through our website. This type of information is amalgamated so that we can build up a picture of how the site is performing.
In addition, when we email you, we may place a tag (also known as ‘tracking pixel’) on the email we send out. These let us monitor performance of our email marketing activity.
Your debit and credit card information
If you use your credit or debit card to donate to us, buy something or pay for an event online or over the phone, we will ensure that this is done securely and in accordance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard. You can find out more information about PCI DSS here – https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/security_standards/index.php
We do not store your credit or debit card details at all, following the completion of your transaction. All card details and validation codes are securely destroyed once the payment or donation has been processed. Only staff authorised and trained to process payments will be able to see your card details.
If we receive an email containing any credit or debit card details, it will be immediately deleted, no payment will be taken and you will be notified about this. All purchases or donations should be completed through the donation page or online shop on our website (www.wizouk.org) or via our Head Office by calling 020 7319 9169.
Under 16s
We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of the young people who engage with us on our website, at events and at schools. Our fundraising events may also request specific information about the age of participants. If you are under 16 and would like to get involved, please ensure that you have consent from a parent or guardian before giving us your personal information. When we collect information about a child or young person aged under 16 we will make it very clear as to the reasons for collecting this information and how it will be used.
Inappropriate website content
If you post or send any content that we believe to be inappropriate, offensive or in breach of any laws, such as defamatory content on our social media pages, we may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your internet provider or law enforcement agencies.
Keeping your personal information
We keep your personal information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected and retained and in line with the legal basis that WIZOuk has for processing it. Where your information is no longer required, we will ensure it is disposed of in a secure manner.
Changes to this privacy policy
We may update the terms of this policy at any time, so please do check it from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address you have provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on our website.
Complaints, compliments or comments
If you are unhappy with our work or something that we have done or failed to do, we want to know about it. We also welcome your views on what we do well. Your comments enable us as an organisation to learn and continuously improve our services. To provide feedback or to lodge a complaint, please contact the Data Protection Officer on 020 7319 9169, email DPO@wizouk.org or write to WIZOuk, Charles House, 108-110 Finchley Road, London NW3 5JJ.
WIZOuk proudly works with the Fundraising Regulator, an independent body which sets and maintains the standards for charitable fundraising.
WIZO supports the following initiatives:
